# Richard M. Williams

310.350.1385 • Torrance, CA 90504 • williamsitv@yahoo.com • www.linkedin.com/in/richmwilliams

• https://rwilliam4444.github.io/ • https://rwilliam4444.github.io/Projects/

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

IT professional with 8 years of supervisory experience, 25 years of windows server administration experience & 6 years of software development\automation experience. Leadership: Supervised 6 employees at TRW and was a Team Lead for 50 plus windows Administrators at IBM on the Disney Account. Planned, designed, built and maintained Windows platform servers in an enterprise environment. 6 years working with automation tools which resulted in minimizing labor hours & reducing human errors on windows related tasks.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**IBM** - work from home

October 2006 - PRESENT

#### Windows System Administrator \ Team Lead \ Software Automation Engineer

- Software Automation Engineer automated windows SA tasks on over 100 IBM supported
  accounts with IPsoft & Red Hat Ansible tools. Some tasks consisted of cleaning disk space,
  archiving event logs, performing CIS related tasks, etc. These activities generated an immediate
  savings in SA labor hours and it also dramatically helped to reduce human errors.
- Team Lead lead team of approximately 50 windows system administrators on the Disney
  account. Responsibilities range from directing, scheduling & assigning project work, training
  new hires, creating \ publishing team room documents, backing up the first line manager, and
  supervising, coaching & counseling staff as required
- System Administrator performed a wide range of activities for over 3000 windows servers on the Walt Disney account (i.e. tool deployments, patching, HBA upgrades, server builds, etc...)

Walt Disney - Burbank, CA

October 1998 - September 2006

## **Senior Systems Administrator - BVHE Division**

- Responsibilities consisted of configuring, installing, and administrating over 60 windows servers.
- Oversaw the operation and maintenance of applicable servers & provided technical assistance in identifying, evaluating & implementing new systems.
- Monitored & maintained hardware, operating systems, & software for 60 plus servers. Interacted with various vendors in order to resolve outstanding issues.
- Provided offsite & onsite support for over 50 remote field sales users located throughout the
   United States and Canada. Support tasks included laptops, DSL \ CABLE modems, routers,

Richard M. Williams 310.350.1385

firewalls, blackberry phones, printers and network switches. Planned, coordinated & scheduled various maintenance & upgrade activities as needed.

Provided 1st, 2nd & 3rd level support to Disney's site-level personnel & maintained, supported,
 & tracked laptop loaner equipment.

# TRW Systems Federal Credit Union - Redondo Beach, CA

August 1993 - October 1998

# **Computer Room Supervisor**

- Supervised, scheduled, trained, & motivated 6 employees. Performed daily processing requirements as established by the Data Processing Mgr.
- Worked with offsite programmers \ engineers to resolve software & hardware problems and also Coordinated the repair & maintenance of office supplies and equipment.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Arts – Bus Admin w\ emphasis in CIS -** Loyola Marymount University, Westchester, CA. Graduated - June 1997

# **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Microsoft Certified IT Professional: sys admin (Retired) self study 2012 MCP ID 981686
- CompTIA Cloud Essentials Professional (Retired) self study 2012 Candidate ID sr5059930
- w2k8 AD configuration & network configuration (Retired) self study 2012 MCP ID 981686
- VMware Certified Professional on vsphere 4 (Retired) self study course in 2010 VCP086781
- MCSA 2003 \ MCSA 2003 Plus MESSAGING (Retired) self study course in 2009 MCP ID 981686
- A+ Hardware Technician Certification (Retired) self study 1998 Verification # is CB0DTT5268
- MCSE Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer (Retired ) self study course in 1998

#### **AWARDS AND HONORS**

### **Thank you Awards - IBM** October 2006 - present

Received over 10 "Thanks Awards" at IBM for work above & beyond what was expected.

#### Go Big or Go Home Award - Disney 2002

- Received an outstanding achievement award from the Disney's BVHE Sales Management team.
- Received spot bonus award from Disney's I.T. management team for outstanding achievement.

#### Beta Gamma Sigma - Loyola Marymount University March 1996

GPA was in the top 5% of my Business Administration class - accepted into Beta Gamma Sigma.